Guide to the Jerome Moross Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Works by Jerome Moross
  - Subseries III.41: Jayhawkers
    - Score: ozalid copy. Reel 1, Part A): "Seal and Main Title." 1B) "Kansas." 1C) "Cam Recovers." 1E-2A) "Jeanne Hides Cam." 2B) "Chopping Wood." 2C) "Jeanne's House." 2E) "Cam's Capture." 3B) "A Smashed Guitar." 3Cx) "Cam Saves Jake." 3C) "Cam Saves Jake." 4B) "Cam Shoots Evans." 5A) "The Stronghold." 5B) "Attempted Assault." 6B) "Raid Montage," Part 1." 6B) "Raid Montage," Part II. 6D) "Cam Riding." 7A) "Love and a Doublecross." 7B) "The Posse." 8B) "Brothers." 8C) "A Raid." 8D) "Accusation." 9B) "Darcy Weakens." 9C) "Cam Arrives." 9D) "Darcy Arrives." 10B) "Premonitions." 10B1) "Premonitions" (continued). 10C) "Zero Hour." 10C1) "Zero Hour," continued. 10D) "Danger Trill." 11A) "The Last Act." 12A) "Prelude to Death." 12B) "Death." 12C) "Finale.", 1958, (113 pages) (Box 30)
    - Score: Manuscript on thin sheets. (See titles from previous file.), 1958, (113 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.42: Jerome Moross Sampler
    - Programs: 2 photocopies., Lyric Theatre, New York, (12 pages, 12 pages) (Box 30)
      [Concert]
  - Subseries III.43: Joan of Arc
    Orchestral Arrangements by Moross.
    - Clipping: review. "The Hollywood Reporter.", 20 October 1948, (2 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.44: Judith Anderson Presentation
    - 1) Score for Parts (4): manuscript in ink. 2) Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets in pencil. 3) Orchestral score: photocopy. 2 copies of 3 pages., (7 pages a.ms.s., 3 pages a.ms., 6 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.45: Jury of Her Peers
    - 1) Score for two pianos: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 3) Manuscript, signed. 4) Text by Susan Glaspell, printed copy., (8 pages a.ms.s., 6 pages a.ms.s., 8 pages a.ms.s., 9 pages) (Box 30)
      [One act opera]
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil on thin sheets., (24 pages a.ms.) (Box 252)
  - Subseries III.46: King David: The Dance Before the Ark
    Adapted from "Le Roi David: Le Danse devant l'Arche" by Arthur Honegger.
    - 1) Score for two pianos: manuscript on thin sheets. 2) Score for two pianos: ozalid copy of copyist's version; 2 copies of 26 pages., 1946, (19 pages a.ms.s., 52 pages) (Box 30)
  - Subseries III.47: Last Judgement
    See also compact disc: Symphony No. 1 (Box 46)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets., 1975, (200 pages a.ms.) (Box 30)
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copy., 1975, (200 pages bd.) (Box 30)
    - Piano score: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Ozalid copy., 1975, (40 pages a.ms.s., 40 pages) (Box 31)
    - Score: manuscript, signed., 1975, (7 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 31)
    - Score for two pianos: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Ozalid copy; 2 copies of 51 pages, bd., 1975, (51 pages a.ms.s., 2 vol.) (Box 31)
    - Tape recording: "Piano 4 Hands," "3 Dances-Orchestral version," "Repeat of Side 1.", (1 cassette) (Box 41)
    - Records (damaged). 1) "The Last Judgement (TLJ): Piano Reduction" and "Three Dances from TLJ." 2) "TLJ: 1" and "TLJ: 3." 3) "TLJ: 2." 4) "Three Dances from TLJ." 5) "TLJ: The Los Angeles Philharmonic." 6) "TLJ: Parts 1, 2, 3" and "TLJ: Parts 8 and 9." 7) "TLJ: Parts 4 and 5" and "TLJ: Parts 6 and 7." 8) "TLJ: Part 10." 9) "TLJ: Excerpts: Three Dances" and "Piano Groove.", (9 discs) (Box 42)
  - Subseries III.48: Life of the Bee
    After Maeterlinck
    - Concert programs: Robin Hood Dell., 1935, (2 vol.) (Box 31)
  - Subseries III.49: Little Mermaid Ballet
    Adapted by Moross from Franz Liszt for a Hans Christian Anderson film.
    - Orchestral scores. 1) Part One "Gnomenreigen": manuscript, signed. 2) Part Four "Underwater Ballet": manuscript, signed. 3) Part Six "Valse Oubilee": manuscript., (10 pages a.ms.s., 14 pages a.ms.s., 35 pages a.ms.) (Box 31)
  - Subseries III.50: Love and Kisses
    - Vocal score: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Ozalid copy; 2 copies of 2 pages., (2 pages a.ms.s., 4 pages) (Box 31)
      [Song from film]
  - Subseries III.51: Love Me
    - Piano score: ozalid copy., (6 pages) (Box 31)
  - Subseries III.52: Make Me Care
    - Vocal score "Reel 3, Part 2": ozalid copies; 3 copies of 3 p., (9 pages) (Box 31)
  - Subseries III.53: Man with a Bear
    Script by Talbot Jennings
    - 1) Orchestral score: ozalid copy. 2) Playscript: mimeograph copy., 30 May 1943, (4 pages, 22 pages) (Box 31)
      [Radio play]
  - Subseries III.54: Mr Fox and Mrs Flye
    Adapted from Ben Jonson's "Valpone."
    - Scenario: carbon copy with signed letter of agreement., (11 pages) (Box 31)
      [A play in music]
  - Subseries III.55: Mountain Road
    - Periodical review: "Daily Variety," Hollywood, California. 23 March 1960, (1 page) (Box 31)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript, signed., 1960, (164 pages) (Box 45)
    - Orchestral score: photocopy., 1960, (114 pages) (Box 45)
    - Score "Can Can": photostat., 1960, (4 pages) (Box 45)
    - Timing chart: photostat; 2 copies of 3 p., 1960, (3 pages) (Box 45)
  - Subseries III.56: Music for the Flicks
    - Program with composer note: Oakland Symphony Youth Orchestra. 11 April 1980, (1 item) (Box 31)
      [A suite of film music for Orchestra]
    - Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil on thin sheets in five parts. 1) Outline and list of parts. 2) I. An Episode in Venice. 3) II. Pastorale. 4) III. Romanza. 5) IV. Habanera and Danzon. 6) V. Nocturnal Procession., 1966, (1 page t.ms., 40 pages a.ms., 27 pages a.ms.s., 31 pages a.ms.s., 40 pages a.ms.s., 17 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 252)
  - Subseries III.57: New Music Revues for Old
    Article written by Moross.
    - Article: "New Theatre" magazine; pgs. 12-13, 33., October 1935, (2 vol.) (Box 31 [COPIES])
  - Subseries III.58: Nocturne
    - Programs with inserts: 1) New Chamber Orchestra (NY). 2) Newspaper clipping, no identified source (photocopy)., 25 February 1934, (10 items, 1 page) (Box 31)
      [Chamber piece]
  - Subseries III.59: Notes on Program
    Written by Moross.
    - Mimeograph copy of Moross' program notes for a concert in which none of his works were played., (3 pages t.ms.) (Box 31)
  - Subseries III.60: One for Me
    - Vocal score: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Published version., 1955 c., (2 pages a.ms.s., 5 pages) (Box 31)
  - Subseries III.61: Paenans
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil, signed. 2) Orchestral score: published version; 3 copies of 16 pages, bd. 3) Programs with announcements: Chamber Symphony Orchestra (NY). 1931; 13 February 1932, (18 pages a.ms.s., 3 vol., 4 items) (Box 31)
      [Concert piece]
  - Subseries III.62: Parade
    See also compact disc: "Underworld."(Box 47)
    - 1) Orchestral score "Letter to the President": manuscript in pencil, signed. 2) Vocal score "Letter to the President": manuscript in the hand of a copyist with ozalid copy; each 7 p., bd. 3) Vocal score "Life Could be so Beautiful": published version; two copies of 5 p., bd., 1935, (16 pages, a.ms.s., 2 vol., 2 vol.) (Box 31)
      [Musical revue. See also compact disc: "Underworld." (Box 47)]
    - Publicity: 1) Program: Guild Theatre (NY); 3 copies. 2) Newspaper clippings including the New York Times and The Boston Globe. 3) Periodical clipping: "The New Theatre," June 1935 with photocopy; 2 copies of 5 p., n.d., March-June 1935, (3 items, 27 pages, 10 pages) (Box 31)
    - Lyrics. Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (16 pages) (Box 49)
    - Miscellaneous notes. Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (5 pages) (Box 49)
    - "Music Notebook." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (15 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Bourgeois Processional." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (52 pages) (Box 252)
    - Orchestral score: "Cock-eyed Finale." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (10 pages) (Box 252)
    - Orchestral score: "Don't Tell Us You're Going." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (36 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Flight from the Soviets." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (30 pages) (Box 252)
    - Orchestral score: "I'm All Washed Up on Love." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (19 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "I'm Telling You, Louie"; pages 9-16A. Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (9 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "I'm Telling You, Louie." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (9 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "I'm Telling You, Louie." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (24 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "I'm Telling You, Louie." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (35 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Join Our Ranks." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (15 pages) (Box 252)
    - Orchestral score: "Life Could Be so Beautiful." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (52 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Marry Me." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (34 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Marry Me: Encore." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (20 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Newsboy-ballet scene." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Newsboy-opening music." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "No Time to Sing a Gay Song Now." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (19 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "On Parade." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (2 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "On Parade." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (26 pages) (Box 252)
    - Orchestral score: "Parade No. 2." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (1 page) (Box 252)
    - Orchestral score: "The Policeman." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (8 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Selling Sex." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (15 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Selling Sex." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (35 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Selling Sex: Encore." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (20 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Send for the Militia." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (15 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Snow from Heaven." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (36 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "Wild Boys on the Road." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (18 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "You Ain't So Hot." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Orchestral score: "You Ain't So Hot"; pages 5-37. Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (33 pages) (Box 49)
    - Score for parts: "I'm Telling You, Louie." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (31 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Dance." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (8 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Don't Tell Us You're Going." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (18 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Don't Tell Us You're Going." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (20 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Fear in My Heart." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (2 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "I'm All Washed Up on Love." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "I'm Telling You, Louie." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Join Our Ranks." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (5 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Letter to the President." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (7 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Marry Me." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (5 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "My Feet are Planted Firmly on the Ground." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (16 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "My Feet are Planted Firmly on the Ground." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (7 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "No Time to Sing a Gay Song Now." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (5 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "No Time to Sing a Gay Song Now." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "No Time to Sing a Gay Song Now." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "On Parade." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "On Parade." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (7 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "On Parade." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (7 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "The Policeman." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (3 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "The Policeman (I Love Boys in Blue)." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (3 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Selling Sex." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (6 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Selling Sex." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (8 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Selling Sex." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (12 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Snow From Heaven." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (8 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Snow From Heaven." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (9 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "The Tabloid Reds." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (16 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "The Tabloid Reds." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (22 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Wild Boys of the Road." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (7 pages) (Box 49)
    - Vocal score: "Wild Boys of the Road." Xerox copy of materials at the Library of Congress., 1935, (7 pages) (Box 49)
      [Gift 1996Gift 1996]
  - Subseries III.63: Peppermint Tree
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript, signed. 2) Publicity: periodical "Film Music" Vol. XII, Jan.-Feb. 1953; p. 18, 1952, (40 pages a.ms.s., 1 page) (Box 32)
      [Animated film]
  - Subseries III.64: Proud Rebel
    - Orchestral score: 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy. 3) Photostat of miniaturized score. Vocal score: 4) "My Rebel Heart": published version. 1958, (118 pages a.ms.s., 117 pages, 54 pages, 3 pages) (Box 32)
    - Microfilm., (1 box/reel) (Box 40)
    - Tape recordings: 2 copies of 2 reels., (4 boxes/reels) (Box 40)
    - Music cues: xerox copy. 1968, (17 pages) (Box 32)
    - Record: "Soundtrack Music from The Proud Rebel.", (1 disc) (Box 42)
    - Records: unidentified., (12 discs) (Box 42)
  - Subseries III.65: Rachel, Rachel
    Original title: "Jest of God." See also compact disc "Valley of Gwangi."(Box 47)
    - 1) Piano score: ozalid copy. 2) Publicity: "Life," Vol. 65, No. 16, 18 Oct 1968, p. 46-53., 1968, (3 pages, 7 pages) (Box 32)
    - Orchestral score: xerox copy., 1968, (85 pages) (Box 32)
    - Orchestral score: xerox copies. 1) Japonica Street; 2 p. 2) Shadow Pictures; 5 p. 3) Accident Fantasy; 5 p. 4) Hand-Kissing Fantasy; 2 p. 5) Auto-Erotica; 7 p. 6) Hysteria; 7 p. 7) Country Walk; 15 p. 8) The Sci-Fi Flick; 7 p. 9) Fantasy Dance; 2 p. 10) Love Scene; 7 p. 11) Pill Fantasy; 2 p. 12) The Cellar Door; 4 p. 13) Down on the Farm; 6 p. 14) End of the Affair; 2 p. 15) Rachel Pregnant; 5 p. 16) The Basement; 2 p. 17) Suicide Fantasy; 6 p. 18) The Operation; 6 p. 19) End Title; 6 p., 1968, (101 pages) (Box 252)
  - Subseries III.66: Ramble on a Hobo Tune
    - 1) Piano score "III- Invention" and "Symphony IIIrd Movement": manuscript in ink, signed. 2) Orchestral score: ozalid copy., (5 pages a.ms.s., 9 pages) (Box 32)
    - Records. "Music from Rachel, Rachel.", (4 discs) (Box 42)
  - Subseries III.67: Recitative and Aria
    - Score for violin: purple hectograph; two copies of 5 p., (10 pages) (Box 32)
  - Subseries III.68: Recitative and Aria
    - Score for Violin: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets. 2) Ozalid copy. 3) Purple ozalid; 2 copies of 4 p., (4 pages a.ms., 4 pages, 8 pages) (Box 32)
      [For Violin]
    - Score for Violin II: 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Ozalid copy., (8 pages a.ms.s., 8 pages) (Box 32)
    - Score for violin and orchestra: manuscript on thin sheets; signed., (10 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 32)
  - Subseries III.69: Recitative and Aria for Violin and Piano
    - Score for violin and piano (drafts): 1) Manuscript, signed. 2) Manuscript on thin sheets. 3) manuscript on thin sheets., 1941, c. 1947, (14 pages a.ms.s., 18 pages a.ms.s., 13 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 32)
    - Score for violin and piano: 1) Ozalid copy. 2) Purple ozalid copy; two copies of 13 p. 3) Ozalid copy, signed; 10 p., bd. 4) Photostat., 1941, c. 1947, (13 pages, 26 pages 1, vol. 18, pages ) (Box 32)
  - Subseries III.70: Roundelay
    - Score: manuscript on transparencies., (272 pages ms.) (Box 32)
      [Orchestral Work]
  - Subseries III.71: Second Battle of Warsaw
    - l) Playscript: mimeograph copy with pencil corrections. 2) Score: manusript, signed. 3) Ozalid copy of score., 1943, (22 pages t.ms, 4 pages ms.s., 2 pages) (Box 33)
  - Subseries III.72: Seven Wonders of the World
    - 1) Music notes: carbon copy. 2) Published publicity brouchure (Stanley Warner Corp.). Scores: signed manuscripts on thin sheets and ozalid copies. 3) "The Holy Land," manuscript; 15 p. 4) "The Mediterranean," manuscript; 8 p. 5) "Rome," manuscript; 5 p. 6) "The Vatican (Beginning),"manuscript; 5 p. 7) "The Holy Land," copy with pencil additions; 2 copies of 15 p. 8) "The Mediterranean," copy; 8 p. 9) "Rome," copy; 6 p. 10) "The Vatican (Beginning)," copy; 5 p. 11) "The Vatican (Ending)," copy; 3 p., 1953, (18 pages t.ms., 1 item, 85 pages) (Box 33)
  - Subseries III.73: Sharkfighters
    See also compact disc "The Valley of Gwangi."(Box 47)
    - Orechestral scores: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Rejected manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 3) "Theme from the Sharkfighters": manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 4) Text to "Restless Lover.", 1956, (94 pages a.ms.s., 3 pages a.ms.s., 3 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages ) (Box 33)
    - Orchestral score: 1) Photostat copy. 2) "Theme from the Sharkfighters," published score. 3) Ozalid copy with additions in pencil., 1956, (57 pages, 2 pages, 94 pages) (Box 33)
    - Microfilm. "Orchestral Score.", (1 box/reel) (Box 40)
    - Score for 30 parts., (352 pages) (Box 47)
      [Gift 1994]
    - 1) Orchestral score: master score in pencil. 2) List of players., (97 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages) (Box 255)
      [Gift 1993]
  - Subseries III.74: Sonata for Piano
    - Program: Pan American Association of Composers Inc.(NY), (1 page) (Box 33)
  - Subseries III.75: Sonata for Piano Duet and String Quartet
    - Scores. 1) Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Score for 4 Parts: ozalid copies with pencil notations. 3) Score: manuscript, signed., 1975, (85 pages a.ms.s., 54 pages, 61 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 33)
  - Subseries III.76: Sonata for Piano Duet and String Quartet
    - Record: "Test Pressing.", 1975, (1 disc) (Box 42)
      [With Flute Concerto]
  - Subseries III.77: Sonatina for Brass Quintet
    - 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Score: manuscript in pencil, signed. 1) Programs: Miami Chamer Ensemble; 3 copies. 1969, (16 pages a.ms.s., 21 pages a.ms.s., 3 pages) (Box 34)
      [Sonatinas for Divers Instruments No 4]
  - Subseries III.78: Sonatina for Clarinet Sextet
    - Orchestral score: 1)Manuscript in pencil on thin sheets, signed. 2) Ozalid copy. 3) Manuscript in pencil. 4) Published music review (no source): original and photocopy., 1966, (35 pages a.ms.s., 35 pages bd., 35 pages a.ms.s., 2 pages) (Box 34)
      [Sonatinas for Divers Instruments No 1]
  - Subseries III.79: Sonatina for String Bass and Piano
    - Orchestral score: 1) Manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Ozalid copy; 2 copies of 24 p., bd. 3) Score: manuscript in pencil., 1966, (24 pages, 2 vol., 32 pages a.ms.) (Box 34)
      [Sonatina for Divers Instruments No 2]
  - Subseries III.80: Sonatina for Woodwind Quintet
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 2) Five parts: manuscript on transparencies. 3) Score: manuscript, signed. 1970, (30 pages a.ms.s., 50 pages a.ms., 39 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 34)
      [Sonatina for Divers Instruments No 3]
    - Orchestral score: 1) Ozalid copy; 30 p. 2) Ozalid copies; 3 copies of 30 p., bd. 3) Score for 5 parts: 3 copies of 5 vol., 1970, (30 pages, 3 vol., 15 vol.) (Box 34)
  - Subseries III.81: Sonatinas
    - Records: "Sonatinas for Divers Intruments." Pro Musica of London., (1 disc) (Box 42)
  - Subseries III.82: Sorry Wrong Number
    - Vocal score: manuscript on thin sheets, signed. 1977, (83 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 35)
      [An opera in one act]
    - Vocal score: manuscript, signed. 1977, (116 pages a.ms.) (Box 35)
    - Score for 23 parts: manuscript on transparencies., 1977, (354 pages) (Box 35)
    - Playscript: mimeograph copy; two copies of 28 p., 1977, (56 pages t.ms.) (Box 35)
    - Programs: Lake George Opera Festival (Glen Falls, NY)., 1977, (4 items) (Box 35)
    - Periodical clipping: Contemporary American Opera Studio., June-August 1980, (1 page) (Box 35)
    - 1) Vocal score: ozalid copy of rehearsal score. 2) Score for two pianos and voices: manuscript, signed., 1977, (80 pages, 116 pages a.ms.) (Box 35)
    - 1) Orchestral score: manuscript in pencil on thin sheets. 2) Correction sheet written in pencil., 1977, (327 pages a.ms., 1 page ) (Box 253)
    - Orchestral score: reduced ozalid negatives with original postal packaging to Moross., 1978, (327 pages) (Box 253)
    - Tape recording: "Orchestral Reading: Lake George Opera.", 1, (reel ) (Box 41)
    - Tape recording: "Orchestral reading: Lake George Opera.", (1 cassette) (Box 41)
  - Subseries III.83: Stevedore
    - Programs: Civic Repertory Theatre (New York City)., 1934, (2 items) (Box 35)
      [Play]
  - Subseries III.84: Symphony No 1
    - Orchestral score: ozalid copy with additions in pencil; 2 copies of 106 p., bd., 1943, (2 vol.) (Box 36)
    - Orchestral score: reduced ozalid negatives., 1943, (146 pages) (Box 36)
    - Orchestral score: manuscript on thin sheets., 1943, (106 pages a.ms.) (Box 36)
    - Parts (30): manuscript on transparencies. 1943, (220 pages a.ms.) (Box 36)
    - Piano score: manuscript on thin sheets., 1943, (42 pages a.ms.) (Box 36)
    - Programs. Philharmonic Orchestra of Los Angeles (6 with 2 inserts); The Philharmonic-Symphony Orchestra, City College of New York (3); Seattle Symphony Orchestra (3); Glendale Philharmonic Orchestra presents the Philharmonic Orchestra of Los Angeles (2)., 1943-1945, (14 items, 2 inserts) (Box 36)
    - Season programs: The Southern California Symphony Association presents the Philharmonic Orchestra of Los Angeles., 1944-1955, (3 items) (Box 36)
    - Publicity: newspaper clippings., n.d., 19 Oct 1943-19 Nov 1944, (28 pages) (Box 36)